[{"question":"<p><strong>What mass of sodium carbonate is in 500cm<sup>3<\/sup> of 0.1M sodium carbonate solution (Na=23, O=16, C=12)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10.6g","106g","5.3g","53g"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<strong>If the rate of diffusion of oxygen gas is 15, what will be the rate of diffusion of methane gas whose relative molar mass is 16?<\/strong><p><\/p>","options":["45\u221a2","30\u221a2","15\u221a2","7.5\u221a2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following cannot be obtained by fractional distillation of petroleum?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hydrogen","Ether","Methane","Butane"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>100cm<sup>3<\/sup> of oxygen is made to react with 50cm<sup>3<\/sup> of hydrogen and the whole reaction mixture was then passed through anhydrous calcium chloride. What is the volume of gas left?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["75cm<sup>3<\/sup>","50cm<sup>3<\/sup>","100cm<sup>3<\/sup>","25cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What volume of 0.5M H<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub> will exactly neutralize 20cm<sup>3<\/sup> of 0.1MNaOH solution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2cm<sup>3<\/sup>","5.0cm<sup>3<\/sup>","6.8cm<sup>3<\/sup>","4.0cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following solutions will give a white precipitate with barium chloride solution and green flame test?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Na<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub>","CuSO<sub>4<\/sub>","CaSO<sub>4<\/sub>","(NH<sub>4<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The function of conc H<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub> in the esterification of ethanoic acid with ethanol is to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["act as a catalyst","serve as a dehydrating agent","serve as oxidizing","serve as a solvent"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following elements in the group one has high polarizing power?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["K","Li","Na","Rb"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following elements are present in detergent builder except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Na","K","P","O"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these elements exhibits catenation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Silicon","Calcium","Iron","Oxygen"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following gases is known as a deodorizer?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["O<sub>2<\/sub>","O<sub>3<\/sub>","SO<sub>2<\/sub>","CO<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 20ml of 1.00m CaCl<sub>2<\/sub> and 60ml 0.20M CaCl<sub>2<\/sub> are mixed, what will be the molarity of the final solution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.20M","0.30M","0.02M","0.40M"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Fluorine does not occur in the free state in nature because","options":["it is a poisonous gas","of its high reactivity","it belongs to the halogen family","it is inert"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The lightest element in the earth's crust is ...<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oxygen","Hydrogen","Carbon","Sulphur"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following terms does not refer to the transition state?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["activated complex","thermal dissociation","excited state","intermediate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>7.30g of a hydrated salt of Na<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub> .xH<sub>2<\/sub>O produces 2.69g of anhydrous salt on heating strongly over a Bunsen flame. The value of X in the above hydrated salt is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","8","10","7"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The substitution reaction between methane and chlorine in ultraviolet light involves the formation of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ions","electrons","free radical","molecules"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following is an example of natural polymer<\/strong><\/p>","options":["glucose","fructose","starch","sucrose"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Epson salt has the chemical formula<\/strong><\/p>","options":["MgSO<sub>4<\/sub>.7H<sub>2<\/sub>O","MgSO<sub>4<\/sub>67H<sub>2<\/sub>O","MgSO<sub>4<\/sub>.5H<sub>2<\/sub>O","MgSO<sub>4<\/sub>.4H<sub>2<\/sub>O"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An unknown element is placed in water. A vigorous reaction takes place and the result is an alkaline solution, of which family is the element probably a member&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["alkaline earth","non-metal","alkali metal","noble gas"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What mass of water is produced when 16.0g of Hydrogen reacts with excess Oxygen?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["144g","36g","72g","16g"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>During the vulcanization of rubber, Sulphur is added to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["break down rubber polymer","binds the rubber molecules together","acts as a catalyst","lengthen the rubber"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the electrolysis of dilute Sulphuric acid using Platinum electrodes, the products obtained at the anode and cathode respectively are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oxygen and Hydrogen","Hydrogen and Oxygen","Sulphur and Oxygen","Oxygen and Sulphur"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following techniques can be used to show Chlorophyll pigment is a mixture of chemical compounds and not a single coloured compound<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["hydrolysis","crystalization","sublimation","chromatography"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following Silver halides is really soluble in Ammonium Hydroxide<\/strong><\/p>","options":["AgCl","AgBr","AgI","AgF"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following derivatives of Nitrogen affords an aqueous solution having a PH of less than 7?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NO<sub>2<\/sub>","N<sub>2<\/sub>O","NO","NaNO<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Cellulose and starches can be classified as one of the following <\/strong><\/p>","options":["isomers","carbohydrates","sugars","hydrocarbons"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Allotropes are element having<\/strong><\/p>","options":["different physical but the same chemical properties","different chemical but the same physical properties","the same physical and chemical properties","the same position in the periodic table"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When air is compressed&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["its density decreases","it solidifies","its temperature increases","its temperature decreases"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pure Sulphuric acid is a liquid of 1.84 density. What volume of it would be required to prepare 500cm<sup>3<\/sup> of 0.2M solution (H=1, S=32, O=16)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.66","3.66","3.00","5.33"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following can have an isomer?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["C\u2082H\u2084","C\u2084H\u2081\u2080","C\u2083H\u2088","C\u2086H\u2086"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following bonds exists in crystalline Ammonium Chloride(NH<sub>4<\/sub>Cl)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ionic and covalent","ionic and co-ordinate","ionic, covalent and co-ordinate","ionic, covalent and metallic"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Water is poured over a white solid and a colourless neutral gas is evolved which burns with a sooty flame. The white solid is?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Calcium Carbonate","Sodium Peroxide","Calcium Oxide","Calcium Carbide"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sodium Carbonate crystals on exposure to a dry atmosphere change to a white powder. This phenomenon is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hygrosopy","deliquescence","efflorescence","sublimation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A gas that behaves as a reducing agent towards Chlorine and as an oxidizing agent towards Hydrogen Sulphide is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NH\u2083","SO\u2082","CO\u2082","NO"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In dilute solution, the heat of the reaction NaOH + HCl -&gt; Nacl + H<sub>2<\/sub>O is -57.3KJ. Therefore, the heat of the reaction<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>2NaOH + H<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub> -&gt; Na<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub> + 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["+28.65KJ","-28.65KJ","+57.3KJ","-144.6KJ"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following substances is used as an anesthetic?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["CHI\u2083","CHCI\u2083","CHBr\u2083","C\u2082H\u2085OH"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that 32g of Sulphur contains 6.02 x 10<sup>23<\/sup> Sulphur atoms, how many atoms are there in 2.7g of aluminium? (Al=27, S=32)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6.02 x 10<sup>23<\/sup>","3.01 x 10<sup>23<\/sup>","6.02 x 10<sup>22<\/sup>","3.01 x 10<sup>22<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When Copper (II) Chloride solution is treated with excess aqueous ammonia, a deep blue solution results. This is due to the presence of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(CuNH<sub>4<\/sub>)<sup>3+<\/sup> ions","(CuCl<sub>4<\/sub>)<sup>2-<\/sup> ions","(Cu (H<sub>2<\/sub>O)<sub>4<\/sub>)<sup>2+<\/sub> ions","(Cu (NH<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>4<\/sub>)<sup>2+<\/sup> ions"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following carbohydrates does not usually occur in the crystalline form?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fructose","sucrose","maltose","cellulose"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a condition for a spontaneous reaction?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["&#916;H - TS is zero","&#916;H - T&#916;S is positive","&#916;H - T&#916;S is negative","&#916;S is zero"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sample of orange juice is suspected to have been contaminated with a yellow dye, which of the following methods can be used to detect the dye?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["decantation","chromatography","filtration","evaporation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following salts in aqueous solution will have a pH greater than 7?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nacl","AlCl<sub>2<\/sub>","Na<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub>","K<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>MO and X<sub>2<\/sub>O represents the formulae of oxides of elements M and X respectively. If M and X should combine together to form a separate compound. What would be the formula of the compound?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["MX<sub>2<\/sub>","M<sub>2<\/sub>X","MX","M<sub>3<\/sub>X<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The decomposition of hydrogen pereoxide is represented by the equation:<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>2H<sub>2<\/sub>O(I)<sub>3<\/sub> -&gt; 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O(I) + O<sub>2<\/sub>(g).<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What mass of hydrogen peroxide would be required to produce 22.4dm<sup>3<\/sup> of Oxygen at s.t.p? (O=16, H=1, molar volume of a gas at s.t.p=22.4dm<sup>3<\/sup>)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["18g","34g","64g","68g"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is suitable for determining different isotopes present in an element which exhibits isotopy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sensitive weighing balance","cathode ray tube","mass spectrometer","Geiger muller counter"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compounds will not decompose when heated strongly?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NaHCO<sub>3<\/sub>","K<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub>","MgCO<sub>3<\/sub>","Ca(HCO<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a reaction is said to be exothermic, which of the following statements is a correct deduction from the information?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the reaction vessel gets hotter as the reaction processes","&#916;H for the reaction is positive","the rate of the reaction increases with time","the activation energy of the reaction is high"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the value of n in the following equation?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>XO<sub>4<\/sub><sup>-<\/sup> + 8H<sup>+<\/sup> + ne<sup>-<\/sup> -&gt; X<sup>2+<\/sup> + 4H<sub>2<\/sub>O<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","4","5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is NOT correct? The 4s orbital<\/strong><\/p>","options":["is defined by the quantum number 1=0","is of higher energy than the 3d orbital","is spherical about the nucleus","is filled before the 4p orbital"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What volume of propane is left unreacted when 20cm<sup>3<\/sup> of oxygen and 20cm<sup>3<\/sup> of propane react according to the following equation:<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>C<sub>3<\/sub>H<sub>8<\/sub>(g) + 5O<sub>2<\/sub>(g) -&gt; 3CO<sub>2<\/sub>(g) + 4H<sub>2<\/sub>O(g)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4cm\u00b3","5cm\u00b3","14cm\u00b3","16cm\u00b3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is likely to have the highest degree of hardness?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["carbonated water","acidified water","rain water","lime water"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>On exposing palm wine to air for some days, it becomes sour owing to the conversion of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["glucose to gluconic acid","ethanol to ethanoic acid","glucose to ethanol","palm wine to palmitic acid"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"}]